Guide to the William McFee Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Acquisitions, 1948-1972 and 1983, 1862-1966, undated; 36.91; (98 boxes) + 1 art
  - Writings, 1893-1963, undated
    - "The Captain of the Vestris" (essay), [1926] November 16 (Box 27)
      Published in the New York Evening Post, 1926 November 24, and in More Harbours of Memory
    - "Captain Sanderson's Wild Oats" (short story), 1934 January 24-March 4 (Box 27)
    - "The Captain's Doll" (short story), 1948 November 26-30 (Box 27)
    - "Cartagena Eroica" (short story), 1923 November (Box 27)
      Published in Shadowland, 1923 March
    - Casuals of the Sea (novel). Notes, [1910 or 1911]; 2 (Box 27)
    - "A Certain Well Known Fruit", no year May 28-29 (Box 27)
    - "The Cheer-Leader in Literature", [1925] November 14 (Box 27)
      Letter to a professor of English at an American university
      Published in Harper's Magazine
    - "Children of the Everlasting Sea" (essay). Autograph manuscript and clipping, 1927 September 13 (Box 27)
      Published in the New York World Magazine, 1927 November; and in More Harbours of Memory
    - "The City and the Sea." Autograph manuscript and typescript, 1913, undated; 3 (Box 28)
    - "Cleanthe." Autograph manuscript and typescript, undated; 4 (Box 28)
    - "The Closing of the Doors" (article). Typescript, undated (Box 28)
      "From American Play Co., Inc."
      Published in Swallowing the Anchor, 1925
    - Command (novel). Notes, undated (Box 28)
    - "Con Amore" (essay), 1923 July 18 (Box 28)
      About Monte Carlo
    - "A Concrete Instance" (short story), undated (Box 28)
    - "Conrad on the Screen" (article), 1929 January 8 (Box 28)
      Review of a film version of Conrad, Joseph, The Rescue, accompanied by a typescript letter, signed, from "Mr. Cooper," Doubleday, Doran & Company, Inc., to McFee, 1929 January 3, and Samuel Goldwyn Productions, "First Information Sheet," carbon typescript
    - "Conversation in Valletta" (article), [1929] February 19-20 (Box 28)
      Published in Library Review, Coatbridge, Scotland, 1929 autumn; and in Brentano's Bookchat, 1929 September-October
    - "Conversation with H. M. Tomlinson", 1932 September 14 (Box 29)
    - Crazy Highlander (biography of Laurence Oliphant). Typescript, 1952; 5 (Box 29)
      Accompanied by a letter from McFee to James T. Babb, and a copy of a letter from Van Wyck Brooks to McFee
    - Crazy Highlander (biography of Laurence Oliphant). Typescript, 1952; 2 (Box 30)
    - "Cruise de Luxe" (novella). Two drafts, 1935 September-December (Box 30)
    - "The Crusaders." Part II, undated (Box 30)
    - "Dawn, On Approaching Genoa-By-Sea" (poem). Typescripts, 1909 November 16 (Box 30)
      Published in East Anglian School Record, Bury St. Edmunds, 1909 December
    - "Decoding the Sea" (essay), undated (Box 30)
    - Derelicts (novel). Galley proof, undated (Box 30)
    - Derelicts (novel), undated; 7 (Box 31)
    - Derelicts (novel). Typescript, undated; 6 (Box 32)
    - Derelicts (novel). Typescript, undated; 2 (Box 33)
    - Derelicts (novel). Clippings and promotional materials (Box 33)
    - "Early Arrival" (short story), undated (Box 33)
    - "Engine Room Stuff." Autograph manuscript and typescript carbon, 1930 November 25-28 (Box 33)
      Published in Harper's Magazine, 1931 February
    - An Engineer's Note Book (essays). Printed, 1921 (Box 33)
    - "England Through English Eyes." Printed, 1922 (Box 33)
    - "Evolution of a Novel." Typescript and typescript, revised, 1928 August 6 (Box 33)
      About McFee's novel Pilgrims of Adversity
    - Family Trouble (novel). Chapters 1-3, and part of 4, 1945 (Box 33)
    - Family Trouble (novel). Second draft, fragment, 1944 (Box 33)
      Not in the final version
    - Family Trouble (novel). Notes and addenda (Box 33)
    - Family Trouble (novel). Typescript, 1948; 3 (Box 33)
    - Family Trouble (novel). Typescript, undated; 3 (Box 34)
    - "Father's Coming Home." Typescript, undated (Box 34)
    - "A Few Words on Mexico" (speech), 1926 (Box 34)
      Later revision published in More Harbours of Memory
    - "A Five Foot Shelf" (essay), [1941] (Box 34)
      About first novels of new writers
      Published in the Providence Journal, 1941 March
    - "The Flaw" (short story). Fragment, [circa 1915 or 1916] (Box 34)
    - "The Fleming Hand Propelled Life Boat", undated (Box 34)
    - "Floating Libraries." Autograph manuscript, fragment, with typescript, revised, 1929 October 27 (Box 34)
      Published in World's Work, 1930 April
    - "Fortune's Favorite", 1914 August 5 (Box 34)
    - "From a Machine Room Window." Typescript, 1916 July 21 (Box 34)
    - The Gates of the Caribbean. Printed, undated (Box 34)
    - "Gentlemen, You May Smoke!", undated (Box 34)
    - "Getting Into Print", [1929] September (Box 34)
      Published in The Colophon, part one, 1930
    - "The Glory of the Sport." Autograph manuscript and carbon typescript, revised, undated (Box 34)
    - "The Golden Calf" (short story), 1927 August (Box 34)
      Accompanied by an earlier draft titled "In the Hurricane Zone"
    - "A Good Physician", undated (Box 34)
    - "A Good Shipmaster", no year August 23-26 (Box 34)
    - "The Grand Tour, or the World Before Your Eyes." Publicity materials, autograph manuscript and typescript carbon, [1930] (Box 34)
    - Great Sea Stories of Modern Times. Introduction and notes, autograph manuscript and typescript, undated; 2 (Box 35)
      Accompanied by correspondence of McFee with Otto v. St. Whitelock and Robert M. McBride, of McBride Company
      Published by McBride Company, 1954
    - "Hale Columbia." Autograph manuscript and proofs, [1924] (Box 35)
      Published in World's Work, 1924 October
    - "The Happy Days." Autograph manuscript and typescript, carbon, 1927 November 19 (Box 35)
    - The Harbourmaster (novel). Typescript, 1932; 2 (Box 35)
    - The Harbourmaster (novel). Galley proof, undated; 2 (Box 36)
    - The Harbourmaster (novel). Typescript, undated; 2 (Box 36)
    - The Harbourmaster (novel). Typescript, undated; 2 (Box 37)
    - Harbours of Memory, undated (Box 37)
      See also: Photographs and Other Visual Materials/Photographs of William McFee
    - Harbours of Memory. Clippings of original stories; typescript, revised; and proofs, 1921 (Box 37)
    - Harbours of Memory. Galley proof, undated (Box 37)
    - "Have You Got Anything to Read?" (Box 37)
    - "I Won't Tell You Where." Autograph manuscript and typescript, carbon, undated (Box 37)
      Published in Holiday, 1930 November
    - "The Immortal Derelict" (essay), [1929] July 17 (Box 37)
      Originally titled "The Ship of Missing Men"
      Published in the New York World Magazine, 1929 September; and More Harbours of Memory
    - "In and Out by the Back Door", undated (Box 37)
    - In the First Watch. Typescript and two carbon typescripts, with printer's annotations, undated (Box 37)
      Published by Random House, 1946
    - In the First Watch. Typescript and two carbon typescripts, with printer's annotations, undated; 4 (Box 38)
    - In the First Watch. Typescript, undated; 3 (Box 38)
    - In the First Watch. Clippings (Box 38)
    - "Jeeny's Folly", undated; 3 (Box 39)
    - "Jerry Stands By", undated (Box 39)
    - "The Kid Across the River", no year July 25 (Box 39)
      Published in Esquire
    - "Knocking Us Galley West" (article), undated (Box 39)
      Reply to an article by Rebecca West, "These American Men," Harper's Magazine
      Published in the New York Times Magazine
    - "The Ladder and the Wall" (short story). Fragment, [1923?] (Box 39)
      Annotated: "MS of Mac's discarded & found in garden on bon fire, Apr 1923"
    - "The Land of Rainbows." Typescript, undated (Box 39)
    - "The Last Night" (poem). Typescripts, revised, undated (Box 39)
      Published in East Anglian School Record, Bury St. Edmunds, 1904 August
    - The Law of the Sea. Typescript, 1948-1950; 6 (Box 40)
    - The Law of the Sea. Typescript, 1948-1950; 2 (Box 41)
    - The Law of the Sea. Page proof, 1951 (Box 41)
      Published by Lippincott, 1950
    - "A Letter in Reply to a Young Gentleman of Yale University." Typescript, 1923 October (Box 41)
      Published in The Bookman, 1923 October
    - "A Letter to a Literary Agent in England." Autograph manuscript and carbon typescript, undated (Box 41)
      Published in The Bookman
    - "A Letter to a Young Gentleman Dissatisfied with Life Ashore", [1925] August 5 (Box 41)
      Published in The Bookman, 1925 November; and in More Harbours of Memory
    - "A Letter to a Young Gentleman Who Wishes to Enter Literature", [1929] February 21 (Box 41)
      Published in The Bookman, 1929 May
    - Letters From an Ocean Tramp. Proof, revised, 1908; 2 (Box 41)
      Purchased from Pharos Books on the Herman W. Liebert Book Fund, 2000
    - Life of Laurence Oliphant, undated (Box 42)
    - The Life of Sir Martin Frobisher. Typescript, typescript carbon, and proofs, 1928 January; 3 (Box 42)
      Illustrations and end papers appeared in an edition published by Harper and Brothers
    - The Life of Sir Martin Frobisher, undated; 3 (Box 43)
    - "The Literary Life at Seventy-Five." Clippings and notes, 1956 (Box 43)
    - "Literature: Its Cause and Cure." Typescript, undated (Box 43)
    - "Little Angevine" (short story). Autograph manuscript, typescript, revised; and typescript carbon, 1927 January 4 (Box 43)
      Earlier draft titled "The Floater"
    - "London Notes on a Best Seller", undated (Box 43)
    - "Looking for Zeppelins." Typescript, undated (Box 43)
    - "Love, and the Man-Eaters." Typescript, 1925 January (Box 43)
    - "McFee on Ships" (newspaper column, The Sun (New York)), 1936 February 29-1938 December 31 (Box 44)
      Includes letters to McFee from the editor of The Sun
    - "McFee on Ships" (newspaper column, The Sun (New York)). Clippings, 1936-1937 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - "McFee on Ships" (newspaper column, The Sun (New York)). Clippings, 1938 (Box 46 (Oversize))
    - "Making Americans", 1946 July 20 (Box 47)
    - "The Match Maker" (short story), no year July 21 (Box 47)
    - "A Mayan Pilgrimage", 1926 August 2-11 (Box 47)
      Published in Harper's Magazine, 1926 December
    - "A Midsummer Caprice", undated (Box 47)
      Includes printed materials relating to J. Fischer & Bro., music publisher
    - "The Moods of Mechanism" (essay), 1927 June 23-28 (Box 47)
      Originally titled "The Mutations of Mechanism"
      Published in Harper's Magazine, 1927 October; and in More Harbours of Memory
    - More Harbours of Memory. Introduction, [1934] (Box 47)
    - More Harbours of Memory. Autograph manuscript, typescript, and publicity material, 1934 April 4 (Box 47)
      Accompanied by a letter from McFee to Robert Cortes Holliday
    - More Harbours of Memory. Clippings of original stories and typescript, revised, [1934]; 2 (Box 47)
    - "Morro Castle Mystery", 1934, 1945-1946; 2 (Box 47)
      Annotated: "N. A. Newspaper Alliance. Not sold; price too small"
    - "My Favorite Character in Fiction: David Copperfield", undated (Box 47)
    - "New Orleans." Typescript, undated (Box 47)
    - "Night Mate" (short story), 1938 October 11 (Box 47)
    - No Castle in Spain. Autograph manuscript and typescripts, revised, with printer's annotations, 1927-1933 (Box 47)
      Includes typescript with revisions by Antonio Llano
    - No Castle in Spain. Autograph manuscript and typescripts, revised, with printer's annotations, 1927-1933; 5 (Box 48)
    - No Castle in Spain. Autograph manuscript and typescripts, revised, with printer's annotations, undated; 2 (Box 49)
    - No Castle in Spain. Typescript, revised, 1933 October 4; 6 (Box 49)
    - No Castle in Spain. Notes, undated (Box 49)
    - North of Suez. Galley proof, undated; 2 (Box 50)
      Includes annotations by Christopher Morley
    - "Notes on a Possible Resurrection" (essay), [1932] (Box 50)
      About H. G. Wells
    - "Notes on the Bennett Journals" (essay), 1932 November 27 (Box 50)
      About Arnold Bennett
    - "Nought Common", undated (Box 50)
    - "Off Nantucket", undated (Box 51)
      Gift of Philip M. Neufeld, 1962
    - "Oil, and the Hairy Ape", 1931 October 3-14 (Box 51)
      Published in Harper's Magazine, 1932 January; and in More Harbours of Memory
    - "Old Glory and the Flag of Convenience", 1959 (Box 51)
    - "The Old Sea Dog", undated (Box 51)
    - "On Discovering an Old Copy of 'Romance'." Autograph manuscript and typescript carbon, 1928 July 2-4 (Box 51)
      Published in George T. Keating's A Conrad Memorial Library (Doubleday, Doran, & Co., 1929)
    - "An Open Letter to Hugh Walpole", undated (Box 51)
    - "Perishable Freight" (short story). Autograph manuscript and typescripts, 1931 June (Box 51)
    - "Pictures and Their Uses" (essay), 1893 November 23-24 (Box 51)
    - "The Pier Head Jump", undated (Box 51)
    - Pilgrims of Adversity (novel). Early plot outline, typescript, revised; and notes, autograph manuscript and typescript, 1924-1928 (Box 51)
      Published by Doubleday, Doran, & Co., 1928
    - Pilgrims of Adversity (novel). Typescript, revised, 1924-1928; 3 (Box 52)
    - Pilgrims of Adversity (novel). Notes, clippings, and correspondence, undated (Box 52)
    - Pilgrims of Adversity (novel), undated; 3 (Box 52)
    - Pilgrims of Adversity (novel), undated; 5 (Box 53)
      Gift of Halstead B. Vanderpoel (Yale 1935), 1951
      Original title: "Sailors of Fortune"
    - "Pilgrim's Progress" (article). Two drafts, no year April 22 (Box 53)
      About vacation in England
    - A Port Said Miscellany. Printed ( Atlantic Monthly ), 1918 March (Box 53)
    - "Prince Chlorophyll", undated (Box 53)
    - "The Public Library of the High Seas." Printed ( Atlantic Monthly ), 1931 June 30 (Box 53)
      Annotated: "For Mrs. Howard and D. A. R. Mag."
    - "The Queen Was in Her Parlor", 1932 January 25 (Box 53)
    - "Quetzals and Questions in Guatemala", no year June 1 (Box 53)
    - Race. Fragment, 1924 (Box 53)
    - Race. Typescript, 1924; 3 (Box 53)
    - Race, undated; 3 (Box 54)
    - The Reflections of Marsyas. Proof, undated; 2 (Box 54)
    - The Reflections of Marsyas. Notes and correspondence, undated (Box 54)
    - "Remittance Man", undated (Box 54)
    - "Romance" (essay), 1928 December 12-14 (Box 54)
      Published in Brentano's Bookchat, 1929 September-October; and in More Harbours of Memory
    - "Rudyard Kipling", undated (Box 54)
      Annotated: "N Y Times Book Rev"
    - "Running Away to Sea." Autograph manuscript; typescript, revised; and typescript carbon, 1935 November 5 (Box 54)
    - "Safety First or Second", undated (Box 54)
    - "The Safety of Life at Sea", 1934 September 19 (Box 54)
    - "Sailor Home from the Sea", 1933 January 7 (Box 55)
    - Sailor's Bane, 1934 August 22 (Box 55)
    - Sailors of Fortune, undated; 6 (Box 55)
    - The Scrap Log of a Privateer (novel), [circa 1910-1911]; 2 (Box 55)
    - The Scrap Log of a Privateer (novel), undated; 2 (Box 56)
    - "A Sentimental Journey." Two typescripts, one revised, undated (Box 56)
    - "The Shadow of Shame." Typescript, undated (Box 56)
    - "Shakespeare and Cranks", undated (Box 56)
    - "The Shining Hour." Galley proof, 1920 (Box 56)
    - Ship to Shore. Autograph manuscript; typescript, revised; and typescript, revised, with printer's annotations, 1941-1943; 3 (Box 56)
      Published by Random House, 1944
    - Ship to Shore. Autograph manuscript; typescript, revised; and typescript, revised, with printer's annotations, 1941-1943; 6 (Box 57)
    - Ship to Shore. Autograph manuscript; typescript, revised; and typescript, revised, with printer's annotations, 5 (Box 58)
    - "Ships Can Be Too Big", 1935 December (Box 58)
    - "Ships That Pass in the Night", undated (Box 58)
    - "Ships Without Hokum", 1934 December 21 (Box 58)
    - A Six Hour Shift. Printed, 1917 April and May (Box 58)
    - "Some Good but Insufficient Reasons for Silence", 1919 October (Box 59)
    - "Some Thoughts on Latin America", 1930 August 12 (Box 59)
    - "The Sordid Side of Literature", undated (Box 59)
    - Spenlove in Arcady. Autograph manuscript, revised; typescript; and galley proof, 1939-1941; 9 (Box 59)
      Includes diagram for "Mudge Place" and preliminary character sketches
      Published by Random House, 1941
    - Spenlove in Arcady. Autograph manuscript, revised; typescript; and galley proof, 1939-1941; 4 (Box 60)
    - Spenlove in Arcady. Autograph manuscript, revised; typescript; and galley proof, 1939-1941 (Box 61 (Oversize))
    - "Startling Exposure of the Base Motives Concealed in Literary Bosoms", undated (Box 62)
    - "Story of Christmas at Sea, Short of Coal", 1927 November 20 (Box 62)
    - "Strange Craft on the Hudson", undated (Box 62)
    - "Summer People", 1951 June (Box 62)
    - "The Sun Was Over the Foreyard", 1932 October 21 (Box 62)
    - Sunlight in New Granada, undated; 3 (Box 62)
    - Sunlight in New Granada. Notes, undated (Box 62)
    - Swallowing the Anchor, undated (Box 62)
    - "Then and Now", undated (Box 62)
    - "A Toast" (poem), 1903 June 28 (Box 62)
      Gift of Dudley Nichols, 1957
      For a dinner in honor of Arthur J. Elder given by John Tweed
      Accompanied by typed letter from McFee to Dudley Nichols, 1952 November 20; a photograph of those attending the dinner; and autographs of attendees, including McFee, Max Beerbohm, Philip Connard, John Tweed, and Albert Rutherston
    - "Too Much of a Good Thing." Typescripts, undated (Box 62)
      Published in East Anglian School Record, Bury St. Edmunds, 1897 April
    - "Training Marine Engineers", 1937 (Box 62)
    - "Trouble Below", undated (Box 62)
    - "Unsolved Mysteries of the Sea", undated (Box 62)
    - "Usquebaugh, or, Water of Life", undated (Box 62)
    - "Valerie, or, Prince Chlorophyll" (opera libretto). Autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 62)
    - "The Washout", 1925 January 25 (Box 62)
    - Watch Below. Typescript, undated; 2 (Box 63)
    - Watch Below, undated; 3 (Box 63)
    - Watch Below. Clipping and quotations, undated (Box 63)
    - "Why I Prefer to Live in the United States." Typescript, undated (Box 63)
    - "Why Not Keep Them Alive", 1936 March 15 (Box 63)
    - "William the Silent", 1935 Februrary 2 (Box 63)
    - "Wine on the Sea", 1931 October 27 (Box 63)
    - "Winged Victories", undated (Box 63)
    - "Wives in Every Port" (essay), 1932 April 16-May 7; 2 (Box 63)
      Published in the Brooklyn Eagle, 1934; and in More Harbours of Memory
    - Other Writings, 1900-1963, undated
      - Book reviews, A-S. Autograph manuscripts and typescripts, undated; 33 (Box 64)
      - Book reviews, T-Y. Autograph manuscripts and typescripts, undated; 32 (Box 65)
      - Book reviews, A-C. Autograph manuscripts and typescripts, undated; 39 (Box 66)
      - Book reviews, D-G. Autograph manuscripts and typescripts, 43 (Box 67)
      - Book reviews, H-L. Autograph manuscripts and typescripts, 35 (Box 68)
      - Book reviews, M-T. Autograph manuscripts and typescripts, undated; 42 (Box 69)
      - Diary, 1911 (Box 70)
      - Diary, 1912 (Box 70)
      - Journal of Impressions, 1912-1913 (Box 70)
      - Diary, 1913 (Box 70)
      - Diary, 1914-1919 (Box 70)
      - Diary, 1927 (Box 70)
      - Diaries, 1930 (Box 70)
      - Diary, 1932 (Box 70)
      - Diary, 1933
      - Diary, 1934 (Box 70)
      - Diary, 1934 (Box 70)
      - Diary, 1934 fall (Box 70)
      - Diary of a bus trip from Miami to New York, 1944 March 5-April 6 (Box 70)
      - Diary, 1944 April-October (Box 71)
      - Diary, 1949 October-1950 October (Box 71)
      - Diary, 1950 October-1951 March (Box 71)
      - Diary, 1951 March-May (Box 71)
      - Diary, 1951 June-October (Box 71)
      - Diary, 1951 October-1952 June (Box 71)
      - Diary, 1952 July-October (Box 71)
      - Diary, 1952 November- 1953 February (Box 72)
      - Diary, 1953 February- May (Box 72)
      - Diary, 1953 June-August (Box 72)
      - Diary, 1953 August-October (Box 72)
      - Diary, 1953 November-December (Box 72)
      - Diary, 1953 December-1954 January (Box 72)
      - Diary, 1954 January-February (Box 72)
      - Diary, 1954 February-March (Box 72)
      - Diary, 1954 March-April (Box 72)
      - Diary, 1954 April-June (Box 73)
      - Diary, 1954 June (Box 73)
      - Diary, 1954 June-August (Box 73)
      - Diary, 1954 August-November
      - Diary, 1954 November-1955 February (Box 73)
      - Diary, 1955 Februrary-June (Box 73)
      - Diary, 1955 June-November
      - "English Journey: Voyage to Lilliput", 1955 (Box 73)
      - Diaries, 1955 July (Box 74)
      - Diary, 1955 November-1956 March (Box 74)
      - Diary, 1956 March-August (Box 74)
      - Diary, 1956 August-1957 January (Box 74)
      - Diary, 1957 January-April (Box 74)
      - Diary, 1957 April-December (Box 74)
      - Diary, 1957 December-1958 August (Box 75)
      - Diary, 1958 July-December (Box 75)
      - Diary, 1959 January-September (Box 75)
      - Diary, 1959 September-1960 July (Box 75)
      - Diary, 1960 July-1961 March (Box 75)
      - Diary, 1961 March-November (Box 75)
      - Diary, 1961 November-1962 June (Box 76)
      - Diary, 1962 June-1963 January (Box 76)
      - Diary, 1963 January-May (Box 76)
      - "Introduction to Tom Cringle's Log", undated (Box 105 (Oversize))
      - Other introductions to writings of others, 1924-1946; 11 (Box 77)
        For more information, see catalog cards in each file
      - "Impressions" (poems), 1919 July (Box 77)
      - Poems, unsorted, undated; 3 (Box 77)
    - Unidentified (articles in Northampton Institute Club Gazette ), 1904 (Box 78)
    - Unidentified (essay on modern poetry), undated (Box 78)
    - Unidentified (letters to editors), 1925-1932 (Box 78)
    - Unidentified (lectures), undated; 3 (Box 78)
    - Unidentified (novel), undated (Box 78)
      Gift of Philip M. Neufeld, 1958
    - Unidentified (novel), 1900 (Box 78)
    - Unidentified (novel), 1939 (Box 78)
    - Unidentified (novel), undated (Box 78)
    - Unidentified, undated; 13 (Box 79)
    - Unidentified, undated; 4 (Box 80 (Oversize))
  - Writings of Others, 1929-1956, undated
    Arranged alphabetically by author.
    - Allingham, Margery. "Smuggled Rum" (novel). Typescript, revised, undated (Box 81)
      Published as Blackkerchief Dick (New York: Doubleday, Page, & Co., 1923), with an introduction by McFee
    - Kipling, Rudyard, undated (Box 81)
    - Knowlton, Robert A., undated (Box 81)
    - McFee, Beatrice Allender. "Personal Commentary", undated (Box 81)
      With notes by William McFee
    - Martin, Donald M., 1956 (Box 81)
    - Maule, Harry E., 1932 (Box 81)
    - Morley, Christopher, undated (Box 81)
    - Rodger, Sarah-Elizabeth, 1929, undated (Box 81)
  - Printed Material, 1909-1964, undated
    Contains mostly clippings, including reviews of writings by McFee, other articles about him, and possibly writings by him. Also present are publications of the Shakespeare Fellowship and other materials relating to McFee's interest in William Shakespeare.
    Additional clippings are present in the Writings and Personal Papers subseries.
    - Shakespeare, William, 1956-1964, undated; 2 (Box 81)
    - Clippings (scrapbook), 1909 (Box 81)
    - Other clippings, undated; 10 (Box 82)
  - Personal Papers, 1862-1966, undated
    Contains legal documents, some relating to McFee's father, merchant ship captain John Henry McFee; records of ship voyages and other papers relating to marine engineering; and scrapbooks containing clippings, writings, photographs, and ephemera.
    Additional clippings are present in the Writings and Printed Materials subseries.
    - Bookplate, undated (Box 83)
    - Biographical information, 1909-1966, undated; 2 (Box 83)
    - Financial papers, 1931-1960, undated (Box 83)
    - Marine engineering, 1938-1964; 3 (Box 83)